Finding aid for News and Information Services (University of Michigan) records, 1900-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library
- University Presidents, 1951-2001
  - Shapiro, Harold T.
    - Press Clippings, undated (Box 172)
    - Resignation, 1987-1992 (Box 172)
    - Salary, 1979-1987 (Box 173)
    - Selection and Inauguration, 1979-1980 (Box 173)
    - Shapiro, Vivian, 1990 (Box 173)
    - Speeches, 1983-1985 (Box 173)
    - University Funding, 1979-1993 (Box 173)
    - Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1977-1978 (Box 173)
  - Bollinger, Lee C.
    - Bollinger, Jean (Box 173)
    - Biographical, 1981-1997 (Box 173)
    - Inaugural Press Kit, 1997 (Box 173)
    - Law Professor, 1977-1989 (Box 173)
    - Law School Dean, 1987-1994 (Box 173)
    - Photographs, circa 1990 (Box 173)
    - Press Clippings, 1996-2001 (Box 173)
    - Recruitment Bans, 1988-1989 (Box 173)
    - Selection and Inauguration, 1996-1997 (Box 173)
    - UM Studies, 1997 (Box 173)
  - Duderstadt, James J.
    - Biographical, 1986-1998 (Box 173)
    - College of Engineering Dean, 1981-1986 (Box 173)
    - Duderstadt, Anne, 1988-1995 (Box 173)
    - Inauguration, 1988 (Box 173)
    - Press Releases (chronological)
      - 1976-1986 (Box 173)
      - June 1988-December 1989 (Box 173)
      - January 1990-June 1992 (Box 174)
      - August 1992-December 1992 (Box 174)
      - 1993 (Box 174)
      - 1994 (Box 174)
      - 1995 (Box 174)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 174)
      - 1998-2001 (Box 174)
    - Professor, 1968-1980 (Box 174)
    - Speeches, 1987-1992 (Box 174)
    - Vice President for Academic Affairs and Provost, 1986-1988 (Box 174)
  - Neal, Homer
    - Interim President, 1995-1997 (Box 174)
- Miscellaneous Files
  The MISCELLANEOUS series is an assemblage of isolated files and scrapbooks relating to specific projects, events, and individuals. Received on separate occasions, the material is physically dispersed throughout the record group. Files on "Project Submich" (Box 35) detail through clippings, reports, and other papers, a research submarine employed to study the Great Lakes in 1967. The Star II, built by General Dynamics, was a two man submarine supported by the United States Coast Guard cutter Woodbine. A small run of Cleland Wyllie topical files in Box 42 include a scrapbook and information on the donation of money and the Fair Lane property in Dearborn by the Ford family.
  - Project Submich, 1957
    - Papers (Box 35)
    - Clippings (Box 35)
    - Tapes (Box 35)
  - Cleland Wylie Topical Files (Box 42)
    - Conference on Science in the Press, March 17-18, 1964 (Box 42)
    - Seminar on managing engineers and scientists, March 3-4, 1966 (Box 42)
    - Ford gift of land and money to U-M, 1956 (Box 42)
      (Fairlane, beginnings of U-M Dearborn)
    - Sesquicentennial celebration, 1966 (Box 42)
    - Scrapbook, 1960 (Box 42)
      (re. development of high resolution radar system at Willow Run laboratories)
  - Partnership 2000 (American-Israeli exchange program), 1995-1997
    Partnership 2000 documentation, covering 1995-1997, includes planning material reports of faculty and student exchanges, photographs, publications (including several Israeli booklets and brochures), and administrative information about University of Michigan involvement with Partnership 2000. Partnership 2000 was an Israeli -- United Jewish Appeal program that linked federated Jewish agencies throughout the United States with geographic units in Israel. Detroit was paired with Central Galilee. Partnership 2000's primary purpose was to foster links between American Jews and Israel, and foster cooperation with other institutions seeking reciprocal roles in improving the quality of life through social, academic, business, technical, and cultural links in the paired regions.
    - Project Documentation, 1995-1997; 3 folders (Box 79)
    - Publications (includes project publicity and information about Negev and Galilee regions of Israel), 3 folders (Box 79)
    - Photographs, 4 envelopes (Box 79)
  - Commencement Addresses, 1990-1996 (Box 174)
  - Miscellaneous Press Clippings, 1983-1992 (Box 174)
  - Photographs (Box 174)
- Audio-Visual
  - Audio-tapes of Information Service news briefs and "actualities", 1973-1975; 15 reels (Box 35)
    (excerpts of newsmakers or events stories) with partial index
  - "Report to the Community", 1975-1980; 16 reels (Box 35)
  - "Tomorrow '98": In the Upper Galilee, VHS Cassette (Box 79)
- Archived Websites, 2010-present
  The ARCHIVED WEBSITES series, 2010-present, documents the output of News and Information Services. Content includes press releases, podcasts, and other news and announcements in a variety of formats. This archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
  - Archived News Services home page, 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Archived News Service Audio Podcasts, 2011
  - Archived News Service Press Releases, 2012-[ONGOING]
Related Material
Because of the size of the News and Information Service record group it has been described in several discreet finding aids in addition to this main finding aid. These include:
University of Michigan. News and Information Services. Series D. (Faculty and staff portraits)
University of Michigan. News and Information Services. Faculty and Staff Files.
University of Michigan. News and Information Services. Podcasts.
Michigan Today